gurparmvir@gmail.com 4436839279

Gurparmvir Singh

Summary

Passionate front-end web developer with experience using HTML5,CSS, JavaScript to build all aspects of the user experience and user interface for client-facing landing pages. Specializes in using React JS and Node JS to build e-commerce sites.

Education

University of Maryland Baltimore County

Bachelor of Computer Engineering • Baltimore, Maryland

05/2020

Community College of Baltimore County

Associate of Science • Essex, Maryland

07/2017

Skills

- HTML5
- JavaScript
- Node.js
- · C++
- Java
- AWS DynamoDB
- API Gateway
- · Rest API
- SQL

· CSS3

- ReactJS
- Expres
- 0
- · AWS Lambda
- · AWS IAM
- JSON
- Python
- PostgreSQL

Experience

Self Taught Web Developer

Design frontend interface and backend services • Baltimore, Maryland

06/2017 - Present

- Design and implement frontend interfaces and backend services to assemble web applications.
- Build function interfaces for mobile-first, dynamic web applications.
- Comprehend mechanisms of servers and deployment of web applications.
- Display understanding of git and github by working on open source projects.

AWS Cloud

Cloud Engineer • Baltimore, Maryland

09/2019 - Present

- Specialize in using AWS lambda and python.
- Used IAM to create users, groups and controlling permissions for serverless applications.
- Created DynamoDB tables using partition keys and sort keys.
- Developed API gateway endpoints for GET, PUT, DELETE and POST of database entities.
- Comfortable in understanding and writing code in serverless.yml.

BPGAS STATION

Manager • Havre de Grace, Maryland

08/2016 - Present

- Design and implement new ideas for customer service and employee satisfaction.
- Increase sales 30% by implementing new specials.
- Increase profits by 15% through effective sales training and troubleshooting.
- Maintain safe, fun working environment.
- · Record inventory usage and reorder supplies as needed.
- Supervise three staff members.
- · Train new team members.
- Monitor the daily activities of three staff members.

Languages

EnglishHindi

• Punjabi

Links

Portfolio - https://gurparmvir.github.io/portfolio/

Linkedln - https://www.linkedin.com/in/gurparmvir-singh-47a950187/

Github - https://github.com/gurparmvir

Certifications

Udemy - Complete web Developer